If you stumble over a roadblock on your WordPress journey, what should you do?
In this lesson, I will guide you on how to find help when you need it the most.
If you are facing an issue such as a formatting problem, a plugin acting up or any other hiccup,
you can start by visiting WordPress.org/support/forums
to see if there's an existing thread that relates to the problem you have.
The answer to your question might already be there.
Let's go ahead and see this in action.
Make your way to WordPress.org, click on Learn and then select Forums.
At the top right, you will be able to search for existing questions.
So in this case, I'm going to type in Website loading slowly
and then I will see a list of results.
And hopefully, I will find the answer amongst these.
If you can't find a thread that provides a solution to your problem,
we can return to the supports forum page and then post a query in one of the support forums,
such as Fixing WordPress or Everything else WordPress.
Let's go ahead and open up the fixing WordPress forum.
At the top right above the list of topics, you can create your own topic
and then fill in all the relevant details about your question.
If you are facing a problem due to a specific plugin or theme,
it is advised to contact their support forum or support page directly.
I also want to highlight that someone from the general support forums
will often refer you to these platforms if the issue is from a theme or plugin.
To find the support forum of a specific plugin or theme, go to the forums page
and scroll down to Themes and Plugins.
Select which one applies, in this case, let's go for plugins
and then search for the relevant plugin.
For this example, I will select the Jetpack plugin.
And then below the download button, I will click on the support tab.
And this will open the support forum for the Jetpack plugin,
where you can search through old questions or create a new topic.
And if you are on your site, you can of course access support via the plugins dashboard.
If you are using a premium theme or plugin, you can always visit their website
and contact their support team.
Lastly, you can access two fantastic resources on the WordPress.org site
that provide help and guidance to use and develop with WordPress.
Firstly, WordPress documentation.
You can access documentation from within the forums page,
or if you click on Learn, and then select Documentation.
The documentation page is a treasure trove of guides and articles
that cover a wide range of topics.
You can use the search block to search for a topic or the links below to narrow down your search.
You might want to learn more about changing or customizing the appearance of your site,
so below customization, we can select Appearance,
and then choose a topic.
We might want to learn more about block themes, for example.
Finally, let's talk about Learn.WordPress.org.
To open the site, click on the Learn tab and then select Learn WordPress.
Learn WordPress is an educational platform and resource that offers a variety of materials,
including video lessons, online workshops, and courses designed to help individuals
learn and enhance their skills in using and developing with WordPress.
I trust these platforms will help you find the necessary answers or resources.
I will also add the links in the description below.